Manuel Pedreira Antón

As a seasoned IT professional with over two decades of experience, I am well-versed in understanding business challenges and designing solutions that align with them. I have a proven ability to manage and coordinate teams of various sizes, including large teams, in fast-paced environments where change and high expectations are the norm.

Work Experience

Feb.2023-Today

DMO Area Manager (IOP), INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña

As part of a departmental restructuring in the Technology division, I am responsible for the support work model for all technology division and the financial control of the Platform department. Apart of my previous dutties my new responsibilities are:

- FinOps Practitioner Hyper Scalar and SaaS budget Control: Definition and implementation for improve the costs and performance for all Platform Services
- Digital Workplace: Engineering and operations of all INDITEX offices (over than 18k computers)

May.2021-Feb.2023

DMO Area Manager (Digital), INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña

As the Head of Digital Management Office for the Digital Department and Zara.com, I was responsible for a wide range of responsibilities and leading a team of 2200 technicians. My role encompasses:

- Budget Control: Strategically manage the department's annual budget of \$150M to optimize resource allocation and ensure financial efficiency.
- Provider Collaboration: Cultivate strong partnerships with more than 300 providers to ensure the delivery of high-quality products and services.

Feb.2019-Feb.2023

SMO Area Manager(Digital), INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña

During my tenure as the Service Management Office Lead at INDITEX, We made a new department to assist all ecommerce operations teams in meeting business requirements (SLA, quality, etc.). Under my leadership, the following transformative projects were successfully execute, significantly improving our operations and performance:

- Implemented a comprehensive ITSM platform that handless 250k cases per year across all technology operations and support functions. This initiative streamlined processes, greatly increasing operational efficiency.
- Created a gitOps-based tool for alerting production issues, adopted by all technical departments at INDITEX(+2000). This tool facilitated faster issue detection, resulting in reduced downtime and heightened customer satisfaction.

Feb.2017-Feb.2019

Systems Architecture Team Lead, INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña

During this stage, I was responsible for carrying out infrastructure projects related to the INDITEX's e-commerce environment. Some of the challenges we worked on during that period were:

- Served as the Infrastructure Team Lead architect, contributing to a project that generated over $98\,\%^a$ of total sales for INDITEX eCommerce platforms.
- Implemented a standardized microservices-based (+3200 µservices) approach, driving efficiency and enabling seamless transformation across the organization.
- Managed cross-functional teams of 100+ professionals, fostering collaboration and achieving project objectives within allocated budgets.

^aHorizon 2022

Oct.2009–Feb.2017 Deputy CTO, INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña

As a member of the Technical Office, I played a pivotal role in defining and managing core IT projects in the eCommerce, system architecture, and operations domains. I successfully delivered impactful projects and assumed the following key responsibilities:

- Designing a new eCommerce datacenter: Spearheaded the development of a robust solution for INDITEX's eCommerce platforms, enabling seamless handling of over 250k orders per hour. Surpassing expectations, we achieved an exceptional performance increase of over 1000 % while maintaining 100% availability.
- Acting as the infrastructure lead for eCommerce platforms: Led the successful launch of Zara.com and other renowned brands in the highly competitive Chinese market. This involved overseeing the infrastructure design and ensuring seamless operations.

Security Technical Manager, INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña Feb.2009-Sep.2009

Systems Architecture Project Manager, INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña Feb.2008-Feb.2009

Systems Architect, INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña Feb.2006-Feb.2008

System Administrator and Support, INDITEX, Arteixo, La Coruña Feb.2004-Feb.2006

May.2003-Feb.2004 System Administrator and Support, Gestoría Nogueira y Álvarez, Ourense

Education

Jan.2015-Jul.2015 Executive Development Programme 2ª Edición, Instituto de Empresa(IE)

Oct. 2011-Nov. 2013 Executive Master of Business Administration (MBA), Univ. Antonio de Nebrija

Software Libre International Master, Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (UOC)

Software Engineering, Universidade de Vigo, Ourense

Management Software Engineering, Universidade de Vigo, Ourense

Certifications

Dic.2023 FinOps Practitioner, The Linux Foundation

Nov.2021 Google Cloud Certified - Cloud Digital Leader, Google

Feb.2020 AZ 900 - Microsoft Azure Fundamentals, Microsoft

Jun.2019 Professional Scrum Product Owner I, SCRUM.net

Oct.2018 SCRUM Master, SCRUM Manager

Jan.2012 ITIL Foundation, ITIL Certification Management Board (EXIM)

Languages

Spanish Native

Gallego Native

English CAE-C1

Other

Jun.2018-Today Web Performance Client Advisory Board Member, AKAMAI

Last Update: 25 de diciembre de 2023